Luoluo Liu

Data Scientist, Philips Research North America, Cambridge, MA, USA 443-255-9100 ★ ○ ★ elydia.777@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Specialized in Machine learning and deep learning, Artificial Intelligence for applications such as classification, regression, object detection, time-series and other applications in the field of signal processing. Proficient using Python, MATLAB to develop prototypes and practical solutions. Extensive experience in health-care industry in 3 healthcare companies with 3+ years experience. Capable of working independently as well as with teams. 4 patent application, 8 invention disclosures and 4 grant proposals.

EDUCATION

Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA

December 2019

Ph. D. in Electrical and Computer Engineering (Machine Learning);

May 2019

M. S. E. in Applied Math and Statistics (Statistics and Optimization)
M. S. E. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

December 2014

GPA: 3.92/4.00

Xinan Jiaotong University, China

 $June\ 2013$

B.S. in Electrical Engineering

GPA: 91.8/100, Rank: 1/425, Outstanding Graduate (2013)

National Scholarship, Ministry of Education of the P.R. China (Top 0.7%)

COMPUTER SKILLS

- · Expertise in Python, MATLAB, R for modeling, simulation, and developing optimization algorithms; data processing and visualization.
- · Proficient in Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib,
- · Proficient in PyTorch, Keras, TensorFlow
- · Experienced with Pyspark, SQL
- · Experienced with Bash script for jobs management in school-owned cluster and AWS
- · Experienced with SVN, Git
- · Word and LATEX for technical writing; Powerpoint for presentations

WORK EXPERIENCE

Philips Research North America, Cambridge, MA

Jan 2020 - present

Data Scientist

- · Analytic and predictive modelling for Philips Patient Flow Capacity Suite (PFCS)
- · Publishing works on Interpretable top comorbidities of recurrent patients and readmission risk
- · Time-series modelling for clinical decision support using EMR, physiological signals and continuous monitoring (respiratory waveform, ECG,PPG, Capnography, breath sound and heart sound) data
- · Writing invention disclosures and grants applications

Selux Diagnostics, Boston, MA

May 2019 - Dec 2019

Algorithm Intern, Algorithm Engineer

- · Addressing data imbalance and reference noise issues in large-scale machine learning problem
- · Developing machine learning in production code (using ETL code and interact with SQL database)

Siemens Healthineers, Princeton, NJ

May - August 2018

Deep Learning Research Intern

- · Developed 2-dimensional and 3-dimensional (3D) Neural Networks for quality assessment of volumetric MR images
- \cdot Built a 3D motion simulation on volumetric and 3D MR images to generate training data for deep learning
- · Use adversarial training for domain adaptation using Generative Adversarial Networks with team

Research Assistant (with Prof. Trac Tran and Prof. Peter Chin)

- · Proposed a framework to improve generalization of neural network to be able to perform images classification using VGG network as well as object detection using Faster R-CNN with arbitrary partial observation ratios
- · Employed sparse Dictionary Learning to Thalamus Segmentation from MRI images for automatic segmentation, even on cases that is challenging for human to delineate the thalamus
- · Created a novel alternative improved method to sparse recovery: a collaborative scheme from multiple bootstrapping samples to improve the performance of regression and studied the theoretical properties
- · Improved the conventional Bagging in sparse regression by reducing the bootstrap ratio and proved the trick theoretically
- · Developed an efficient Partial Face Recognition algorithm using Dictionary Learning approach to test on partial image patches without retraining
- · Developed the reconstruction algorithm of Random Replicate Mirror Imaging System to perform system calibration and recovery of the scene pictures
- · Proposed a novel and robust blind watermarking scheme based on wavelet tree
- · Solved the Interference Alignment for MIMO wireless communication problem numerically

Teaching Assistant

September 2014 - May 2018

- · Courses: Compressed Sensing & Sparse Recovery; Wavelets & Filter Banks; Intro. to ECE
- · Worked with non-experts; Conveyed complicated ideas in simple ways; Coordinated with other TAs and the lab manager

PUBLICATIONS

• Operational Research:

LuoLuo Liu, Dennis Swearingen, Eran Simhon, Chaitanya Kulkarni, David Noren, Ronny Mans, "Interpretable Identification of Comorbidities Associated with Recurrent ED and Inpatient Visits," to appear in EMBC 2022 Eran Sinhom, **LuoLuo Liu** "Improvements of readmission risk score," talk in AMIA, CIC

• Ensemble Methods:

LuoLuo Liu, Sang P. Chin, Trac D. Tran, "JOBS: Joint-Sparse Optimization from Bootstrap Samples," https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.03743, arxiv, submitted to Information Theory pdf

LuoLuo Liu, Sang P. Chin, Trac D. Tran, "JOBS: Joint-Sparse Optimization from Bootstrap Samples," *IEEE International Symposium on Information Theory (ISIT)*, 2019

LuoLuo Liu, Sang P. Chin, Trac D. Tran, "Reducing Sampling Ratios and Increasing Number of Estimates Improve Bagging in Sparse Regression," *Accepted at 53rd Annual Conference on Information Science and Systems (CISS)*, 2019 [invited paper] pdf

• Image Processing and computer vision (natural, medical imaging, OCT imaging)

Gouthamaan Manimaran, Urmila Airsang, Soumabha Bhowmick, Abhijith Girin, **Luoluo Liu**, Carol Lane, Dheepak S, Celine Firtion, Pallavi Vajinepalli, Kumar T. Rajamani, "Evaluation Tool to Diagnose Faults and Discrepancy in Semi-Automated or Manual Annotations in Ultrasound Cine Loops (Videos)," to appear in EMBC 2022

Jasper R. Stroud, **Luoluo Liu**, Sang P. Chin, Trac D. Tran, Mark A. Foster, "High speed optical coherence tomography using real time compression to achieve 72 MHz A-scan rates," *Optical Express*, 2020

Arun Nair*, **LuoLuo Liu***, Akshay Rangamani, Sang P. Chin, Muyinatu A L. Bell, Trac D. Tran, "Reconstruction-free Deep Convolutional Neural Networks for Partially Observed Images," *GlobalSip 2018* (Joint first authors) ppt, pdf

Silvia Arroyo-Camejo, Benjamin Odry, Xiao Chen, Kambiz Nael, **LuoLuo Liu**, David Grodzki, Mariappan S. Nadar, "Towards Contrast-Independent Automated Motion Detection Using 2D Adversarial DenseNets," *International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine (ISMRM 2019)*

LuoLuo Liu, Xiao Chen, Silvia Bettina Arroyo Camejo, Benjamin L. Odry, Mariappan S. Nadar, "Motion Determination for Volumetric Magnetic Resonance Imaging using a Deep Machine-learning Model," *US Patent*

LuoLuo Liu, "Jeffrey Glaister, Xiaoxia Sun, Aaron Carass, Trac D. Tran, Jerry L. Prince, Segmentation of Thalamus from MR Images via Task- Driven Dictionary Learning," *SPIE medical Imaging 2016* pdf

LuoLuo Liu, Trac D. Tran, Sang P. Chin, "Partial Face Recognition: A Sparse Representation-based Approach," *IEEE Conf. on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing(ICASSP), 2016* pdf

Dung N. Tran*, **LuoLuo Liu***, Trac D. Tran, Sang P. Chin, Jeffery Korn, Eric T. Hoke, "Compressive Coding via Random Replicate Mirror," *GlobalSip 2016* (Joint first authors) pdf